Since American Idol star Taryn Southern started composing music with AI in 2017, musicians all over the world have begun wondering about the implications of AI and modern technology where music production is concerned.
自从《美国偶像》明星塔琳·萨瑟恩2017年开始用人工智能作曲，世界各地的音乐人便开始思考：就音乐制作而言，人工智能和现代科技会带来哪些影响。
AI is perceived by some as a helpful tool in the creation of music and by others as almost “the beginning of the end”.
有人把人工智能视为音乐创作的有用工具，也有人几乎把它视为“终结的开始”。
In Taryn’s case, AI software enabled her to communicate melodies and chords that she didn’t know how to put together herself.
就塔琳而言，人工智能软件使她能够表达出一些自己不知如何组合的旋律与和弦。
The end product was therefore a collaborative effort, rather than a piece entirely produced by technology.
因此，最终成品是合作的成果，而不是完全由技术制作出来的作品。
Taryn’s story has a distinctly positive feel that highlights the advantages of using AI in music production.
塔琳的故事明显给人一种积极的感觉，凸显了在音乐制作中使用人工智能的优势。
AI can serve as a source of inspiration, and as an ideal jumping-off point should a musician be hit with writer’s block.
人工智能可以充当灵感的来源；万一音乐人遭遇文思枯竭，它也可以充当理想的起点。
Rather than seeing AI as a tool, some musicians consider it to be hugely detrimental to the music scene.
一些音乐人不把人工智能看作工具，而是认为它对音乐界危害极大。
At the moment, because such technology is still so young, the music it’s producing is not necessarily what we want to hear.
目前，由于这类技术还非常稚嫩，它制作出来的音乐不一定是我们想听的。
In short, it’s not of great quality.
简而言之，这样的音乐质量并不高。
Those who have produced their own music, or even fans of authentic, artistic music, will also argue that a computer could never emulate the work (and human touch) of a true musician.
自己制作过音乐的人，甚至是纯正而富有艺术性的音乐的爱好者，也会争辩说，计算机永远不可能模仿真正音乐人的创作（以及人情味）。
Music has been an integral part of the story of humans for ages; in fact, the first known piece of music is believed to be around 3,400 years old.
长久以来，音乐一直是人类历程中不可或缺的一部分；事实上，已知最早的乐曲据信有大约3400年的历史。
Songs have long been used as a means of communicating messages and folk stories, covering everything from societal ethics to world history.
人们历来把歌曲当作传播信息和民间故事的一种手段，内容涵盖从社会伦理到世界历史的方方面面。
Since many people see music as such an inherently human expression, it is often considered too precious to impart to technology.
由于很多人把音乐看作一种本质上就属于人类的表达方式，它往往被认为太过珍贵，不能托付给技术。
The thought of a computer generating a “random” piece of music that hasn’t been painstakingly created by an artist is almost seen as sacrilegious.
计算机生成一首并非由艺术家苦心创作的“随机”乐曲，这样的想法几乎被视为亵渎神圣。
Regardless of which side of the argument you fall on, it seems likely that the use of AI in music production will only become more frequent.
无论你站在这场争论的哪一方，看来人工智能在音乐制作中很可能只会用得越来越频繁。
Our modern world is preoccupied with technological advancements.
我们这个现代世界一心关注着科技进步。
Instead of shying away from the idea of this bleak future, we would do best to approach it with optimism and curiosity.
我们最好不要回避这种暗淡未来的设想，而要以乐观和好奇的心态去面对它。
While there are always bound to be stubborn old-school musicians who refuse to use tech, music producers should consider AI as something to be embraced.
尽管总免不了会有一些固执的老派音乐人拒绝使用科技，但音乐制作人应该把人工智能视为值得欣然接纳的事物。
AI music software is still very much in its infancy, but with more investors interested in the development and outcomes of such technology, and considering the rapid growth rate of other tech advances in recent years, it’s only a matter of time before AI-produced music is seen as the new norm.
人工智能音乐软件仍完全处于起步阶段，但随着更多投资者对这类技术的发展和成果感兴趣，再考虑到近年来其他科技进步增速之快，人工智能制作的音乐被视为新常态只是时间问题。